<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>cloud-native on Luthadel</title><link>https://rudeigerc.dev/tags/cloud-native/</link><description>Recent content in cloud-native on Luthadel</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>zh-Hans</language><copyright>© 2020 Yuchen Cheng. This site is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution 4.0 International license.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 22:44:05 +0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rudeigerc.dev/tags/cloud-native/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Cloud Native Infrastructure: Part 2 Monitoring</title><link>https://rudeigerc.dev/posts/cloud-native-infrastructure-monitoring/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 22:44:05 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rudeigerc.dev/posts/cloud-native-infrastructure-monitoring/</guid><description>Introduction Prometheus Prometheus is an open-source systems monitoring and alerting toolkit.
Installation In docker-compose.yml:
services:prometheus:image:prom/prometheusrestart:alwaysvolumes:- ./prometheus.yml:/etc/prometheus/prometheus.yml- ./prometheus:/prometheusports:- 9090:9090user:rootPrometheus provides a UI at :9090 by default.
Node Exporter Node Exporter is designed ad a Prometheus exporter for hardware and OS metrics exposed by *NIX kernels.
According to the documentation, it&amp;rsquo;s not recommended to deploy it as a Docker container because it requires access to the host system, so you could just download the binary release version.</description></item><item><title>Cloud Native Infrastructure: Part 1 Service Discovery</title><link>https://rudeigerc.dev/posts/cloud-native-infrastructure-service-discovery/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2019 22:23:43 +0800</pubDate><guid>https://rudeigerc.dev/posts/cloud-native-infrastructure-service-discovery/</guid><description>Introduction Service discovery components maintain a list of service instances that are available for work within a microservice domain, which is the most important part in microservice architecture. The advantage of service discovery components is that clients do not need to know the exact position of services, what they have are just the registered name of services if they want to call or use them.
Usually, a microservice will register itself to the center of service discovery components when it was started successfully, including necessary parameters such as the unique name of service, IP address and the port bind.</description></item></channel></rss>